准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
弃白痴逃命
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜指导
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
上班十八小时的痛苦终于结束了
End of another 18-hour shift of misery
你们好啊
Ahoy there
你们两个小子
And what are you two laddies
这周末有什么计划
have planned for this weekend?
我要给小蜗的壳做抛光
I'm polishing Gary's shell
我要参加一场后后前现代
Well, I'm going to a post-post-pre-modern
非构成派舞蹈表演
unconstructivist dance performance
那可
Well, that's uh
真是迷人
fascinating
不必做那堆无聊事了
Instead of that malarkey
你们想不想周末登上我的全新游艇
what would you say to a leisurely weekend sailing trip
来场航海旅行呢
on me brand-new yacht
阳光照在你脸上
The sun in your face
清风吹在你
The wind in your, uh
抬头纹上
head wrinkles
我倒可以来一场轻松愉快的航海旅行
Well, I wouldn't mind a nice relaxing ocean cruise
好
Great
明天一大早码头见
I'll see you at the dock bright and early tomorrow morning
第二天早上
酷乐湖
沙丘 码头
蟹老板  我已经打扮齐全准备好要
Mr. Krabs, I'm all dressed up and ready to
潜泳了
snorkel
等一下
Wait a second
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
你的船呢
Where's your ship?
有种可疑的味道
Something smells fishy
可别让后桅弯曲变形了
Don't get your mizzenmast in a twist
游艇
实木 组装
涂料 展示
你们要的船就在这
I got your ship right here
需要一点组装
Some assembly required
必须自己把船组装起来
We have to build the ship
能自己把船组装起来了
We get to build the ship
旱鸭子才坐预制的船
Premade vessels are for land-lubbers
真正的水手都自己造船
Real sailors build their own ships
现在快去干活  你们两个
Now get to work, you two
作为一名老海军
And as an old navy man
我就来负责最难的那部分
I'll be responsible for the most difficult part
敢问最难的部分是
And that would be
在旁边监督
Supervising
豪船杂志
老海军
Old navy man
老懒鬼还差不多
More like old lazy man
可真是
Oh, boy
好了  来把事成了吧
All right, let's get this over with
说明书在哪
Now where are the instructions?
我来找
I'll find them
说明书  说明书
Instructions, instructions
如何组装
How to assemble
找到了
Got them
第一步
Step one
快给我
Give me that
现在我们该怎么办
Now what are we supposed to do?
别担心  章鱼哥
Don't worry, Squidward
我知道要怎么处理这种情况
I know exactly how to handle this situation
真的吗
Really?
只要跟随内心  凭感觉走
We just need to follow our hearts
章鱼哥  第一块完成了
Squidward, I did the first piece
海绵宝宝  你这傻蛋
SpongeBob, you clam head
不能先安桅杆
You don't put up the mast first
说什么  章鱼哥
What's that, Squidward?
我说
I said
海绵宝宝  你这傻蛋
SpongeBob, you clam head
必须先从骨架装起
You have to start with the frame
好了  把它弯成船形
All right, now bend it into a boat shape
挠挠挠挠挠挠
Tickle, tickle, tickle
海绵宝宝  木板不是用来
SpongeBob, wood planks are not
挠的
ticklish
尝试组装骨架很多次之后
建成了  章鱼哥
We did it, Squidward
来握个手
Put her there
万岁
Hooray
你到底是在搞什么鬼
What in the name of all that's salty are you doing?
你这是在浪费贵得要命的木材
You're wasting expensive lumber
我们这是在给船组装骨架  蟹老板
We're trying to build the ship's frame, Mr. Krabs
组装骨架
Building the frame?
可是
But
预制船骨架
骨架早都给你准备好一份了
They give you one all ready to go
来看一看  小子
Take a gander, boyo
我状态良好  蟹老板
I'm shipshape, Mr. Krabs
成了船的形状
快回去干活
Now get back to work
就快要退潮了
The tide's going out
钉子
死也钉不下去是吧
A stubborn one, eh?
章鱼哥
Squidward
你有看到过一座锚吗
Did you see an anchor?
我锚好像掉了
I think I dropped one
不然交换位置行不
Why don't we switch places?
你在这下面干活  我在那上面干活
You work down here and I'll work up there
安全多了
Much safer
不在白痴底下干活
Never work below an idiot
小心上面
Look out above
上面
Above?
都够了
That's it
章鱼哥
嗨  章鱼哥
Hi, Squidward
你在上面有看到过一座保险箱吗
Have you seen a safe up here?
我保险箱好像掉了
I think I dropped it
从现在起你就到我旁边干活
From now on you're working next to me
方便我盯着你
where I can keep an eye on you
那可太棒了  章鱼哥
That's so sweet, Squidward
尝试组装游艇更多次之后
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
你的船组装好了
Your ship is finished
基本上长得像船的就当成船了
We use the term "ship" very loosely
感觉有点不对头
She's a little off the beam
明白了
I know
只要再漆上去一层闪亮的涂料就好了
All she needs is a nice shiny coat of paint
海洋秘方号
海洋秘方号准备好启航了
The S.S. Sea-cret Formula is ready to set sail
只要拖进酷乐湖里就能开了
as soon as you two drag her into the lagoon
救生员
前进
Mush
好吧  至少这周末并没完全被浪费
Well, at least this weekend isn't a total waste
你先别急  章鱼哥先生
Not so fast, Mr. Squidward
你还有工作要做
You still have work to do
工作
Work?
蟹堡王
欢迎光临海上蟹堡王的盛大揭幕仪式
Welcome to the grand opening
of the Krusty Krab of the high seas
这里价格更高
and even higher prices
想都别想
Forget it
我一步都不会从这地方挪开
I am not moving from this spot
没问题
No problem
菜单
但是在船上
好兴奋啊  章鱼哥
How exciting, Squidward
我能一边翻肉饼一边
I get to flip patties and be
晕船了
seasick at the same time
咱可不在酷乐湖上面卖什么吃的
We're not gonna sell any food in the middle of a lagoon
我要来份蟹黄堡套餐
I'd like one Krabby Patty combo
上面多加套餐
with extra combo on it
你的餐好了
Your order
稍息  水手
At ease, sailor
我都不知道酷乐湖有座小岛
I didn't know there was an island in Goo Lagoon
正前方有屁股山
Butt-burg, dead ahead
所有人都抓紧了
Everyone, hold fast
竖笛资讯
海神王的鼻毛啊
Great Neptune's nose hair
请来一份双层蟹黄堡
One double Krabby Patty, please
酷乐湖
把你们这所有蟹黄堡都给我
Give me all the Krabby Patties you got, kid
我已经饿到都能去海之霸用餐了
I'm so hungry, I can eat at the Chum Bucket
甚至还能喜欢上
and like it
告诉你们吧
Boy, I'll tell you
老天啊
Oh, boy
墙中殿堂
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
小蜗
Oh, Gary
谁想吃点心
Who wants snackies?
快过来  小蜗
Come on, Gar-bear
我保证过你数学得A的话会给你点心
I promised you a treat if you got an A on your math test
快过来  小蜗小蜗小蜗
Here, snaily, snaily, snaily
蜗牛点心
你在哪  小蜗
Where are you, boy?
小蜗
Gary?
墙上突出来的那块一直都会喵喵叫吗
Did that lump in my wall always meow?
小蜗  你是怎么进去的
Gary, how'd you get in there?
我又要怎么救你出来
And how do I get you out
欢迎
完了
Oh, no
我把自己反锁起来了
I locked myself in
我到处找你找好久了  小先生
I've been looking all over for you, little mister
快过来
Here, boy
谢谢你  好心的陌生人
Thank you, kind stranger
你是谁啊
Who are you?
你可以叫我沃利C
You can call me Wally C
墙 壁
因为我就住在墙里
for in these walls I live
看吧
You see?
我叫做海绵宝宝
Well, my name be SpongeBob SquarePants
因为我是块穿方裤子的海绵
for I'm a sponge who wear square pants
你是怎么进来的
How did you get in here?
很久以前
Long ago
我是个杂务工
a handyman was I
直到
till
出售
我被永远关了起来
me eternal confinement
那玩意正常吗
Is that normal?
房子一点小问题没啥大不了
That's just the house settling
成交
Sold
于是  我的命运被永远抛进了墙里
And thus, me fate was forever cast in drywall
讲完了
The end
什么
What?
你居然一直都住在墙里
I can't believe you've been living in the walls all this time
也许我们能一起找到办法出去
Maybe we can find a way out together
凡进入这个被约束的世界就没有出口
There be no exit once ye enter this restrictive realm
你不想出去吗
Don't you want to get out of here?
才不想
Nay
沃利已经不再关心外面的世界了
Wally no longer cares for the outside realm
在这  拥挤狭窄只是一种心态
Here, feeling cramped be just a state of mind
欢迎来到墙中殿堂
Welcome to Wallhalla
想不想来参观一下
How would you like a grand tour?
我们想参观参观
We would love the grand tour
欢迎光临我的霉菌园
Welcome to me mold garden
我的曲霉菌
Me aspergillus
去  去
Shoo, shoo
你花园里还种了葡萄干
I see you're also growing raisins in your garden
葡萄干
Raisins?
不对
Oh, no
那些是海胆粪蛋子
Those are urchin droppings
沃利  有个出口
Wally, there's a way out
才不是
Nay
那只是我的魔法冰箱
That's just me magic fridge
嫩肚肚海草汁
有魔法
Magic?
不管我吃多少喝多少
No matter how much I eat or drink
冰箱都会再变出来不少
she always provideth more
我也有嫩肚肚海草汁
I get tender tummy kelp juice, too
不过还得是魔法冰箱里的更好喝
Sure tastes better from the magic fridge, though
墙中殿堂还有不少神奇缝隙
There be many magical crannies in Wallhalla
墙中殿堂甚至还有魔法药柜
Wallhalla even has a magic medicine cabinet
我在这放了
where I keep
我的魔法鼻刷
me magic nose brush
刷刷鼻子里头的毛
Brush the hairs within your nose
这样才不会掉衣服上
so they don't drip upon your clothes
墙中殿堂太神了
Wallhalla is amazing
墙背后是个无忧无虑的世界
To think that right behind the wall
想想就感觉很美好
is a world without problems
墙中殿堂其实有一个毛病
Well, Wallhalla does have one problem
有个很吵的邻居
A noisy neighbor
不会吧
No
在墙外面
Beyond these walls
住着一只穿着吱吱叫鞋子的生物
there lives a creature with squeaky shoes
整天到处跺脚
who stomps around all day
一只无时无刻欢欢乐乐尖叫的怪物
A monster who shrieks with delight at all hours
一只会发出刺耳尖笑的野兽
A beast with an ear-piercing laugh
烦得让我都疯了
So annoying, it drove me mad
声音差不多是这样的
and it sounds like this
那是我听过最难听的声音了
That's the most horrible thing I've ever heard
不过我真的好高兴
But I'm sure glad
能跟你平平安安跟你在一块  沃利
to be safe in here with you, Wally
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
能认识你就是我一生中最棒的一天了
Meeting ye has been the greatest day of me life
还是说现在晚上了吗
Or is it night time?
我好几年前就没时间概念了
I lost track years ago
你想不想来参加交友宴
What say ye to a friendship feast?
那当然可以了
I thought you'd never ask
为友情干杯
To friendship
敬墙中殿堂
To Wallhalla
沃利  这是我吃过
Wally, that was
最具友情的一场盛宴了
the friendliest feast I ever had
看来我跟小蜗
Well, I guess me and Gary
得去找回去的出口了
better find our way back home
谁
Who's
谁是小蜗
Who's Gary?
就是  我的宠物蜗牛小蜗
You know, my pet snail Gary
你的宠物蜗牛
Your pet snail?
是我的宠物蜗牛才对
He be my pet snail
而且那也不叫小蜗
And his name ain't Gary
而是小瓜
It's "Garr-ee"
看见没
See?
小蜗
明白了
I get it
小瓜
"Garr-ee"
小蜗
Gary
真好笑
That's funny
那四处出没的笑声
That haunting laugh
原来就是你
It was ye
你烦得我都疯掉了
Ye who drove me mad
我诅咒你  海绵宝宝
I curse thee, SpongeBob SquarePants
还有你烦人的笑声
and thy irritating cackle
我要从你身上的洞拧出水来
Now I'm gonna wring the water from your pores
滚出墙中殿堂
Be gone from Wallhalla
你在破坏我美丽的世界
You are breaking me beautiful world
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
在吗
You're home?
要是你不马上出来的话
If you don't come out right now
看来不在
Guess not
那好  他家就是我家
Well, su casa es mi casa
真不敢相信
I don't believe it
是葡萄干
Raisins
别想逃
No, you don't
派大星  救命
Patrick, help us
这片子好垃圾
The show stinks
烂
Boo
快递到了
The mail is here
不是寄给我的
Well, this isn't for me
就退还给寄件人好了
I'll just return to sender
快下去
Go down
不是寄给我的饼干
Not-for-me cookies
派大星  谢天谢地你来了
Patrick, thank goodness you're here
能不能出去  海绵宝宝
Do you mind, SpongeBob?
我还在用洗手间
I'm using the bathroom
不好了
Oh, no
我穿越了魔镜
I'm through the looking glass
墙中殿堂灭亡了
Wallhalla has been destroyed
你们毁了我窄小又不适的生活
Ye ruined me narrow, uncomfortable life
那爱哭鬼是谁
Who's the cry baby?
外面的世界肯定会有你想念的东西
There has to be one thing
from the outside world that you miss
对吧
Right?
等等
Wait
那是蟹黄堡吗
Is that the Krabby Patty?
好吧  我承认有我想念的东西
Okay, I admit there was one thing I missed
我十几年来
I've had to ration
只能限量吃这么一个蟹黄堡
this one Krabby Patty for decades
我好像有办法了
I think I have an idea
派大星  我妈的饼干怎么浮在马桶上
Patrick, why are my mom's cookies floating in the toilet?
我应该是忘记冲水了
I guess I forgot to flush
蟹堡王
上菜了
Order up
还是应该说  下菜了
Or should I say, order down
谢谢
Thank ye
此处点餐
有芥末酱吗
Got any mustard?
我还是恨那笑声
I still hate that laugh